<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles About Montessori Education on Montessori Bloom</title>
    <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles About Montessori Education on Montessori Bloom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 18:42:05 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://montessoribloom.org/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Observation Guidelines</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/observation_guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/observation_guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Observation Guidelines Note: Because of the importance of establishing the children&amp;rsquo;s work period routine, we do not take visitors during the first ~2 months of the school year. We kindly ask for your patience and understanding.
Welcome! Thank you for taking the time to visit us.
During your observation, you may notice that the teacher is focusing her attention more on maintaining a stable work environment in the classroom than on introducing new lessons to the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Life Exercises</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/practical_life_exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/practical_life_exercises/</guid>
      <description>The exercises of Practical Life resemble the simple work of life in the home: sweeping, dusting, washing dishes, etc. These purposeful activities help the child adapt to his new community, learn self-control and begin to see himself as a contributing party of the social unit. His intellect grows as he works with his hands; his personality becomes integrated as body and mind function as a unit.  &amp;mdash; Reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Out</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/going_out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/going_out/</guid>
      <description>Going out is not a field trip. A field trip is planned and organized by the teacher and the whole class goes out together under the teacher&amp;rsquo;s lead. In contrast, going out is a work that the child initiates and carries out.
During the 1st plane of development (birth to age 6), children need to adapt both to the environment of their family and to the life that family is living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Responsibility</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/freedom_and_responsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 17:52:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/freedom_and_responsibility/</guid>
      <description>We help children prepare for their life not only for middle school or high-school.
 Dr. Maria Montessori said that her method was to give aid to all aspects of life.
It was through Dr. Maria Montessori&amp;rsquo;s observations of children that she recognized the constructive power within any human person. That observation made her significantly aware of the importance of liberty. However, it is not liberty on its own that will allow for the positive construction of human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>