<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Montessori Bloom</title>
    <link>http://montessoribloom.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Montessori Bloom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 18:45:34 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://montessoribloom.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Observation Guidelines</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/observation_guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/observation_guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Observation Guidelines Note: Because of the importance of establishing the children&amp;rsquo;s work period routine, we do not take visitors during the first ~2 months of the school year. We kindly ask for your patience and understanding.
Welcome! Thank you for taking the time to visit us.
During your observation, you may notice that the teacher is focusing her attention more on maintaining a stable work environment in the classroom than on introducing new lessons to the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Life Exercises</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/practical_life_exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/practical_life_exercises/</guid>
      <description>The exercises of Practical Life resemble the simple work of life in the home: sweeping, dusting, washing dishes, etc. These purposeful activities help the child adapt to his new community, learn self-control and begin to see himself as a contributing party of the social unit. His intellect grows as he works with his hands; his personality becomes integrated as body and mind function as a unit.  &amp;mdash; Reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four Planes of Development: The 2nd Plane</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/second_plane_of_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/second_plane_of_development/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Maria Montessori said that the first 24 years of life are made up of four planes of development:
 The 1st plane &amp;ndash; birth to 6 years old The 2nd plane &amp;ndash; 6 to 12 years old The 3rd plane &amp;ndash; 12 to 18 years old The 4th plane &amp;ndash; 18 to 24 years old  The 1st and 2nd planes of development are complementary and they constitute childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Out</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/going_out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/going_out/</guid>
      <description>Going out is not a field trip. A field trip is planned and organized by the teacher and the whole class goes out together under the teacher&amp;rsquo;s lead. In contrast, going out is a work that the child initiates and carries out.
During the 1st plane of development (birth to age 6), children need to adapt both to the environment of their family and to the life that family is living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-05</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-05/</guid>
      <description>May Newsletter Room 302 Monday, May 20th, 2019
Dear Parents,
Thank you very much for your support for our fundraising event, Laps for Lincoln. One of the rewards (challenges) our students wanted was eating lunch in the classroom. Some of my former students join me for lunch on Fridays, so when we had our lunch in our classroom a couple of weeks ago, our classroom was quite crowded but was filled with joyful talk and laughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-04</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-04/</guid>
      <description>April Newsletter Room 302 Monday, April 22th, 2019
Dear Parents,
Our students have started practicing Taiko drumming. They have learned some basic facts about playing Taiko: using the wrist to strike the drum rather than using just their arm muscles, saying the different sounds we make in Taiko, which is called kuchisho-ga, and teamwork. Their enthusiasm for learning and memorizing the movement is amazing. Each grade is learning a different song right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-03</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-03/</guid>
      <description>March Newsletter Room 302 Friday, March 29th, 2019
 “The child is endowed with unknown powers, which can guide us to a radiant future. If what we really want is a new world, then education must take as its aim the development of these hidden possibilities.” &amp;ndash; Dr. Maria Montessori
 Dear Parents,
Thank you very much to those parents who signed up to help us out for our Taiko Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-02</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-02/</guid>
      <description>February Newsletter Room 302 Monday, February 25th, 2019
Dear Parents,
February was a hectic month to be sure; I want to sincerely thank all of you for your support for both me and our class.
I shared with you in my January Newsletter that we as a class read the book, Peace Week, and have been putting into practice some of the principles we learned. This month, we have been learning about Desmond Tutu and Martin Luther King, Jr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-01</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2019-01/</guid>
      <description>January Newsletter Room 302 Saturday, January 19th, 2019
Dear Parents,
Happy New Year to you all!
First of all, I would like to thank you for the generous gifts I received at the end of the first semester. Thank you so much for your love and support. I am blessed by having all of your children in my classroom but you have blessed me even more!
In Japan, many children and adults start the new year by doing calligraphy writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-12</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-12/</guid>
      <description>December Newsletter Room 302 Monday, December 17th, 2018
Dear Parents,
We have had a busy last several weeks with things such as our iReady mid-year assessments, practicing making origami cranes, making Christmas/holiday ornaments, writing Christmas/holiday cards, writing winter stories, making “gingerbread man” stories, winter poems, and all of our normal Montessori works! I cannot forget to mention that we have been practicing songs for our gathering this Friday, December 21st. We are going to celebrate our first semester of this school year with songs, tea, and origami.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-11</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-11/</guid>
      <description>November Newsletter Room 302 Wednesday, November 21st, 2018
Dear Parents,
Just a couple of weeks before our Thanksgiving Break, our class worked hard on writing that will be made into a real book. Thank you very much for responding to me despite the short notice. I have submitted everyone’s writing before our break. The books that were ordered will arrive just before our winter break. The title is “Winter Wonderland with All of Us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-10</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-10/</guid>
      <description>October Newsletter Room 302 Monday, October 29th, 2018
Dear Parents,
Thank you very much for coming to our Parent/Teacher Conferences. (There are a couple more conferences left and I am looking forward to seeing those parents as well!) It was nice to see all of you and get to know more about you and your child. I asked several parents about their hopes/dreams for their children. Some of your responses include “I want my child to have the joy of learning”, “I want my child to continue to be artistic”, “We want our child to love him/herself”, “We want our child to be happy and have self confidence”, “I want my child to be living their full potential”, “We want our child to pursue his/her passion”, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-09</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 17:22:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-09/</guid>
      <description>September Newsletter Room 302 Monday, September 24th, 2018
Dear Parents,
Thank you very much for signing up to assist with our laundry, flower arrangement, and community snack program. Thank you also so much for purchasing materials for our class to use from our Amazon wish list. Your support helps and keeps our classroom a joyous learning place for the students to work. Thank you also for having your child bring milk cartons to our classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-08</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 18:15:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-08/</guid>
      <description>August Newsletter Room 302 Monday, August 27, 2018
Dear Parents,
Welcome back to school!
Thank you very much for coming to our Open House and /or Back to School Night last week. It was great to meet and see you all. I am looking forward to working with you this year.
Following are a list of things I spoke about at our Back to School Night:
 About Me (Please find this on my website at montessoribloom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Responsibility</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/freedom_and_responsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 17:52:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/freedom_and_responsibility/</guid>
      <description>We help children prepare for their life not only for middle school or high-school.
 Dr. Maria Montessori said that her method was to give aid to all aspects of life.
It was through Dr. Maria Montessori&amp;rsquo;s observations of children that she recognized the constructive power within any human person. That observation made her significantly aware of the importance of liberty. However, it is not liberty on its own that will allow for the positive construction of human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>