<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Montessori Bloom</title>
    <link>http://montessoribloom.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Montessori Bloom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 18:45:34 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://montessoribloom.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-09</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 17:22:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-09/</guid>
      <description>September Newsletter Room 302 Monday, September 24th, 2018
Dear Parents,
Thank you very much for signing up to assist with our laundry, flower arrangement, and community snack program. Thank you also so much for purchasing materials for our class to use from our Amazon wish list. Your support helps and keeps our classroom a joyous learning place for the students to work. Thank you also for having your child bring milk cartons to our classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-08</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 18:15:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/newsletter/2018-08/</guid>
      <description>August Newsletter Room 302 Monday, August 27, 2018
Dear Parents,
Welcome back to school!
Thank you very much for coming to our Open House and /or Back to School Night last week. It was great to meet and see you all. I am looking forward to working with you this year.
Following are a list of things I spoke about at our Back to School Night:
 About Me (Please find this on my website at montessoribloom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Responsibility</title>
      <link>http://montessoribloom.org/article/freedom_and_responsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 17:52:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://montessoribloom.org/article/freedom_and_responsibility/</guid>
      <description>We help children prepare for their life not only for middle school or high-school.
 Dr. Maria Montessori said that her method was to give aid to all aspects of life.
It was through Dr. Maria Montessori&amp;rsquo;s observations of children that she recognized the constructive power within any human person. That observation made her significantly aware of the importance of liberty. However, it is not liberty on its own that will allow for the positive construction of human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>